Fengxian…
凤仙…
I want to be with the daughter she left behind.
我想和她留下的女儿在一起
That was all I wished for.
这就是我唯一的心愿
It can't be helped if she hates me.
被怨恨也是无可奈何
Even so, I wanted her near me.
即使如此 我也想将她留在身边
But I lost the game this time.
不过 既然输了棋局
I'll let it go for now.
这次就先放弃吧
Speaking of, that man…
是说 那个男人…
I can't forgive him.
不可原谅
He placed his hand on my daughter's shoulder three times during the match!
在对弈中竟然把手 放在女儿的肩膀上三次
What should I do to get back at him?
该做些什么来泄愤才好呢？
So you're finally awake?
你终于醒了啊？
You're buying out one of our courtesans.
既然说要来为我家娼妓赎身
I'm sure you know that a couple of thousand silvers
应该知道只掏出一、两千银
just won't cut it.
是买不起的吧？
Of course I do.
我知道啦
If 10,000 silvers aren't enough, I'll pay 20 or 30.
一万银两不够的话 两、三万我都会出的
A hundred thousand may be too much.
但要是十万就有点难了
I see. In that case,
这样啊
hurry up and follow me.
那就快过来选个喜欢的吧
Geez.
真是的
Even the Three Princesses are taking part?
三姬也加入没关系吗？
I said pick whoever you like.
我都说要让你选喜欢的了
But they won't be cheap.
当然也会收更多钱就是
What should I do?
真麻烦啊
No matter how well-dressed the courtesan,
无论娼妓如何盛装打扮
they only look like go pieces.
看在我眼里就是棋子
In that case, perhaps I should
既然如此
pay back my debts to Meimei, who helped me out a lot.
不如就选梅梅 当作对我好的回报也不错吧
Sir Lakan.
罗汉大人
I have my pride as a courtesan.
我也是有着身为娼妓的尊严
If you desire me,
大人若是希望如此
I will not hesitate to leave with you.
那我就不会有任何犹豫
However,
但是…
I do hope you're choosing properly.
既然要选 就请大人慎重地选吧
Meimei! Don't open that without my permission!
梅梅 不准擅自打开！
What are you doing!
你在做什么？
Wait!
给我站住
A flower that's beautiful even after it has wilted.
即使枯萎也依然美丽的花
If that had any sort of message…
如果那意有所指的话…
Could it be…?
难道是…
Kitty cat, kitty cat
小小猫唷
Cries out wondering where that child is
那孩子哭呀哭的
Where that child is
不知在何处？
The little birds
什么都不晓得的
Without knowing anything
小小鸟儿们
Flew away far
向着遥远的天空
Far up the sky
一去不复返
Kitty cat, kitty cat
小小猫呀
Good night for now
现在该睡了
Until tomorrow
明日再见面
What are you doing? This room is for sick patients!
你在做什么？这是病人的房间！
Get out now!
还不快出去！
Go choose a courtesan over there!
赶快回去选个娼妓就是了
Yes.
对啊
I have to choose.
得选一个才行
Listen to me!
你有在听吗？
I want this woman.
就这名女子了
Don't be stupid!
说什么傻话！
You're the one who said that I could pick whoever I want.
选谁都可以 是婆婆你说的吧？
I'll pay any price you say.
要多少钱我都会出
Be it 100,000, 200,000. Anything.
十万还是二十万 我都会付
Don't be stupid!
你在说什么？
Let's play go.
我们来下棋吧
I see, that's your move?
哦 走这步啊？
Your moves are always so unexpected.
你的行动总是出乎意料呢
Now I know where Maomao gets it.
猫猫这点跟你很像呢
Big Sister!
大姐
If only you had been honest from the beginning…
你若是一开始能坦率点就好了
Why didn't you tell him sooner?
为什么就不能早点…
I'll buy out this courtesan right here.
我要为这位娼妓赎身
This woman,
宛如凤仙花般
who's as beautiful as balsam.
美丽的这名女子
Basen was the one
陪着我一起把那个男人
who accompanied me in taking that man
送到绿青馆的
to the Verdigris House.
是马闪
I'm tired.
好累啊
That conniving family…
阴险的父女…
That's Concubine Loulan.
那是楼兰妃
She must have stayed behind after the garden party.
游园会结束后 他们还留在这儿啊
That man must be Concubine Loulan's father who pushed to get his daughter
那个男人就是把女儿强行送进后宫
into the rear palace.
楼兰妃的父亲吗？
But even so,
就算如此
I wish he wouldn't make comments about a high official right here.
还是希望他 别在这种地方说高官的坏话
If anyone heard,
要是被人听到
they would think I was a part of it.
我可能也会被误会在说坏话呢
He's still young, that one.
他还是太年轻了
Hey.
喂
Sir Jinshi is calling for you.
壬氏大人叫你过去
Good work today.
辛苦你了
No, it was nothing.
不会 没什么
-Oh no, you got so skinny! -I'm all right.
-哎呀 你变得这么瘦 -我没事啦
Here, Xiaomao. Eat up!
来 小猫 多吃一点
I'll bring you more!
我等会儿还会再拿菜过来
I thought that you hated the Sir General.
我还以为你对军师大人怀恨在心呢
Sir Jinshi.
壬氏大人
I don't hate him.
小的并不恨他
From my end,
就小的立场而言
it's because of his great aim that I'm here today.
还多亏他一发命中 所以才能在这儿
You had no other way of phrasing that?
你就没有别的说法吗？
I mean, it's true.
这就是事实
I don't know what you thought had happened,
小的不知道您是做了何种想象
but a courtesan can't get pregnant without consenting to it.
但娼妓若不同意 是怀不了孩子的
They have contraceptives and abortion pills,
娼妓会服用避孕药和堕胎药
and in the early stages, they can get abortions.
即使在怀孕初期也能够打掉孩子
She gave birth to me because she wanted to.
会生下孩子 是因为她有这个意愿
I think he was the one who got tricked.
不如说 他才是中计的一方
The Sir General was?
军师大人吗？
Women are cunning creatures.
女人是狡猾的生物
If they can read the cycle of their blood flow, they can predict
只要能解读经血的周期 就能够大致预测
generally when they're most likely to get pregnant.
容易怀上孩子的时日
If they're courtesans,
若是娼妓的话
they can write letters to adjust the dates of the visit.
还能寄信请对方更改来访的日子
That's why she lost her mind
正因为如此
when her plot did not work out…
当她的目标落空时 才会气到发狂吧
So much that she did not care about hurting herself.
疯狂到不惜伤害自己
And not only that,
甚至还不满足
she even sent the baby's pinky along with the letter.
连婴儿的小指都附在信里送了出去
Sir Jinshi.
壬氏大人
That man
那个男人
only spoke to you at your office, isn't that right?
没有在书房之外和您说过话吧？
Now that you mention it…
这样说来…
That man can't recognize people by their faces.
因为那个男人认不出人脸
What do you mean?
认不出？什么意思？
He can recognize eye and mouth shapes,
他虽然能认出眼睛和嘴巴的形状
but not all of them together.
但合起来就认不得了
He sees all faces as the same.
在他看来 所有人都长得一样
-That must be difficult for him. -Yes.
-那肯定吃了很多苦吧 -是
My adoptive father who told me about this said the same thing.
告诉我这件事的养父也是这么说
He's had a difficult time.
他是个可怜人
He has suffered for a long time because of his condition.
因为这个毛病 吃尽了苦头呢
I see.
这样啊
But, for some reason,
但不知为何
he can recognize me and my adoptive father by our faces.
他却能认清我和养父的脸
Apparently, he's strangely obsessed with me for that reason.
那种莫名的执着 似乎也是源自于此
Sir Jinshi, if that monocled face said,
壬氏大人 要是那个单片眼镜说：
"Call me Papa," what would you think?
“叫我爹爹” 您会有何感想？
-I'd want to shatter his glasses. -Right?
-我会想打烂他的眼镜吧 -对吧？
He wants to call himself a father,
他虽然坚称是我的父亲
but he's just a sperm donor.
但不过是个种马罢了
Did that man realize the meaning of the dead rose?
那个男人应该注意到 枯萎玫瑰的意思了吧？
If he didn't, that's none of my business.
就算不知道 也没关系就是了
I may dislike him, but I don't wish him ill will.
我虽然讨厌他 但并不恨他
The only thing I thank him for, is me becoming Luomen's daughter.
他使我能成为罗门的女儿 我很感谢
You say that, but you looked like you hated him a lot.
说是这么说 但你的讨厌方式很露骨啊？
You don't get it, do you, Sir Jinshi?
壬氏大人还不够了解他呢
When I tried to stop the festivities,
小的在阻止祭祀的时候
I was helped by that man.
曾受到那男人的帮助
I'm sure he sensed that something was about to happen.
他当时应该就察觉有事情要发生
The Sir General did?
军师大人吗？
But he didn't know anything at the time.
但他那时应该什么都不知道才是
He doesn't collect proof and build theories like me.
他不像我要搜集证据再做出推测
He senses fishy things when they're happening
他是凭直觉来判断事有蹊跷
and his senses are rarely wrong.
而他的直觉很少出错
Frustratingly, he's very lazy and doesn't act on his own.
令人生气的是 他因为嫌麻烦 所以不会自己动手
If that man had openly acted on his suspicions,
要是那个男人公开展开行动
the elixir of immortality may have been in my hands
现在也许就已经将返魂妙药
at this very moment!
弄到手了也说不定
I know that this is only jealousy.
我明白 这就是嫉妒
That man is so talented that Old Man praises him so openly,
明明拥有能让老爹盛赞的才能
and yet,
那个男人
he doesn't understand the talent he was blessed with!
不知道自己拥有多么得天独厚的才华
We can't make him our friend,
虽然没办法成为同一阵线
but we shouldn't make him our enemy.
但最好也别与他为敌
I understand.
我知道了
What's wrong, sir?
怎么了吗？
Well… In this world,
不 只是希望你知道…
there are no fathers who want to be hated by their children.
这世界上没有父亲会喜欢被讨厌的
A few days after returning to the rear palace,
回到后宫几天后
I received a small package from Big Sis Meimei.
梅梅姐姐送来了包裹
Inside was a letter
里面有封信
explaining who bought out who,
写着谁替谁赎身了云云
and a beautiful piece of fabric.
还放着一条美丽的布帛
Listen up, Maomao.
听好 猫猫
The day I'm bought out, you'll dance for me, won't you?
等到我被赎身那天 你要好好为我跳舞哦
I wanted to see Big Sis Meimei off.
原本是想替梅梅姐姐送行的
That courtesan who is
比谁都还温柔的…
more beautiful than anyone.
那位娼妓
I didn't know I still remembered all the steps.
没想到我都还记得呢
Hey!
喂
-What are you doing? -Sir Jinshi.
-你在搞什么啊？ -壬氏大人
Why are you here?
您为什么在这儿？
I received a report that a strange woman was climbing the outer walls.
既然又获报有奇怪的女子爬上了外墙
Of course I had to do something!
我就只能来处理了吧？
I thought no one could see me…
我还以为神不知鬼不觉呢
That was naive of me.
还是穿帮了啊
Don't make me work too hard.
别给我添麻烦啊
You didn't need to come, Sir Jinshi.
壬氏大人也不必特地来一趟吧
You could've sent someone else.
请其他人来不就好了？
A kind guard recognized your face
是好心的卫兵认得你的长相
and came to speak with me first.
所以先向我传话的
You think no one notices you,
就算你认为自己很低调
but that's not true for other people.
但旁人可不是这么想的
-Remember that. -Yes, sir.
-记好了 -遵命
Now, it's my turn to ask the questions.
那么 轮到你回答了
What were you doing?
你在做什么？
In the pleasure district, whenever a courtesan is bought out,
在花街 替被赎身的娼妓送行时
the other courtesans dance to send her off.
其他的娼妓都会跳一支舞
-What is it? -Nothing.
-怎么了？ -没有
I didn't know you could dance.
只是没想到你会跳舞啊
It was a part of my basic training.
作为基本教养的一环 被逼着练的
I'm already hearing rumors.
外面都在传着谣言
About the eccentric buying out a courtesan.
说那个怪人要替一位娼妓赎身
I'm sure you have.
是呢
He also requested some days off.
他还顺便提了休假
He'll be taking a ten-day vacation.
好像打算休息整整十天
He's causing so much burden on others.
真会给人添麻烦呢
My sister told me in a letter.
姐姐寄来的信中也有提到
They'll be having a feast for seven days and seven nights.
何止三天三夜 说是要办七天七夜的宴会
I don't know how much money he paid to buy her out,
虽然不晓得赎身花了多少钱
but from the number of those lamps,
不过看那灯火灿烂的样子
it must have been an obscene price.
绝非其他的娼妓能相比
Even so,
但是
the courtesan that was bought out never makes an appearance.
得到赎身的娼妓不会出现在人面前
The allure behind the Verdigris House increases more and more.
绿青馆的传闻一定会越传越广
Just as Grams planned, huh?
正合了老鸨的意
In the end,
话说回来
who did Sir General end up buying out?
军师大人究竟是替谁赎了身呢？
I have no idea.
不知道 会是谁呢？
I'm sure you know.
你知道的吧？
No matter how beautiful she was, she could never beat you, sir.
不论是什么美女 都比不过壬氏大人的美貌
That's not an answer.
这可不算回答
You didn't deny my comment though!
竟然不否认吗？
The woman he bought out
那个男人赎走的女子
won't be in this world for much longer.
已经活不了多久了
When I was at the brothel,
我在青楼时
no one ever talked about the woman who gave birth to me.
从未有人提过生下我的女子
I'm sure Grams made sure no one talked about her.
一定是老鸨封的口吧
But talk like that
但是
can spread around from the smallest of slips.
这种事会从细枝末节透漏出来
The fact that I'm the reason that the Verdigris House
让绿青馆险些倒闭的原因
almost shut down completely.
就是我自己
About the identity of the woman who,
这个因缺了鼻子而感到耻辱
embarrassed of her missing nose,
一直疏远自己的女人
kept me far away.
到底是谁呢？
That nightmare was something that happened in real life.
那个恶梦是真实发生过的事情
I have no memory of the woman as a mother.
我没有那女人身为母亲的记忆
All I have now is a deformed pinky.
留下的只有扭曲的小指
It all has nothing to do with me.
不过 已经与我无关了
I found happiness as Luomen's daughter.
能做为罗门的女儿 我已经很幸福了
-Sir Jinshi. -What is it?
-壬氏大人 -怎么了？
Did you know that fingertips can grow back?
指尖即使切掉 也还会长回来哦
Don't say that now.
现在适合说这个吗？
What are you doing?
你做了什么？
My scar opened up again.
伤口又裂开了
What are you saying?
不是一句裂开就没事了吧！
I think my body got hot because I danced.
我还以为是跳舞身体才发热的
My sense of pain is dull, I think because of my drug experiments.
因为药物实验的关系 我的痛觉变得很迟钝
It's all right. I'll stitch it up now.
没事的 我马上就缝起来
No!
住手！
Sir Jinshi. Let me stitch this.
壬氏大人 这样没办法缝
Don't do it here!
别在这儿缝！
Hey, Sir Jinshi…
那个 壬氏大…
Please let me down.
请放我下来
Your scar will get worse!
你的伤口会扩大的
What if someone sees us?
被看到的话怎么办？
It's too dark. No one will see.
四下黑暗 没人会看到的
And it's my second time carrying you like this.
何况 这样抱你已经是第二次了
Right. The day I passed out from my injuries…
因为受伤晕过去的那次啊…
Sir Jinshi.
壬氏大人
I know this might not be the time,
抱歉挑在这个时候
but there's something I've been meaning to say to you.
但小的一直有件事想和您说
What is it? You're being so formal.
怎么了 突然这么郑重？
It's something very important.
这件事无论如何都得说
I have to say it to you.
是非常重要的事情
Just say it out loud.
那你就快点说吧？
Sir Jinshi…
壬氏大人…
Please give me my calculus bovis.
请赐牛黄给小的
Don't tell me you never had it!
您该不会没准备吧？
Hey! Watch your manners!
不准胡说失礼的话！
Geez.
真是的
A head butt? So immature.
突然用头锤也太孩子气了
But it feels nicer to talk to him
不过算了 跟这样孩子气的人
when he's being a little immature.
说起话来还比较轻松呢
Wow…
呵呵…
Maomao!
猫猫
Sir Jinshi is here!
壬氏大人来了哦
Yes, ma'am!
是
Excuse me.
恕小的失礼
Are you feeling well?
你身体恢复了吗？
Yes. Everyone takes great care of me at the Jade Pavilion.
是 多亏翡翠宫的大家照顾
Did you need me for something?
话说 大人有什么吩咐吗？
It's nothing.
没什么
I just heard something interesting.
只是听到了些有意思的事
I have a favor to ask of you.
我有事情想拜托你
Oh, this again?
原来如此 又来了吗？
So, what should I do to assist you this time?
那么 究竟需要小的做什么呢？
Maomao's story has only just begun.
猫猫的故事才正要开始
What sorts of cases would she get mixed up in this time?
她下次又会卷入什么样的事件呢？
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：杨易